{"tossups": [{"question": "George Stoneman\u2019s failure at this battle may have been the reason for the Union defeat. Oliver Otis Howard\u2019s 11th Corps were encircled in this battle when Stonewall Jackson secretly moved around their flank. The Union commander at this battle quipped, \u201cMay the Lord have mercy on General Lee for I will have none,\u201d shortly before his troops were forced back across the Rappahannock River. For ten points, Joseph Hooker was defeated by Robert E. Lee in what 1863 battle near a Virginia village?", "answer": "Battle of<b> Chancellorsville</b> (accept<b> Chancellorsville</b> campaign)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "In this country, students wore yellow T-shirts to protest increased phosphorite mining in L\u00a8a\u00a8ane-Viru [LAH-neh VEE-roo] County. This country experienced the Era of Silence under Konstantin Pats in opposition to the Vaps Movement. This country\u2019s army, led by Johan Laidoner, fought together with the White Russians in a War for Independence that was ended by the Treaty of Tartu. For ten points, name this nation where people demonstrated at the Tallinn Song Festival Grounds.", "answer": "Republic of<b> Estonia</b> (accept<b> Eesti</b> Vabariik)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "A prime minister from this party supported a 10% goods and services tax in his country and served four terms from 1996 to 2007. Robert Menzies and Malcolm Fraser were among the leaders of this party, as was Tony Abbott during the tenure of Julia Gillard when this party was the Opposition. In a 2019 election, this party\u2019s leader, Scott Morrison, was elected as prime minister. For ten points, what is this Australian political party that opposes Labor?", "answer": "<b> Liberal</b> Party of Australia", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {"question": "This policy was expanded by the Scott Act, which prohibited re-entry to the United States. Support for this act was drummed up by Denis Kearney and the Workingman\u2019s Party. This act was preceded by the less-comprehensive Page Act and later repealed by the Magnuson Act. Supporters of this act blamed\u201ccoolies\u201d for depressed wages in places like San Francisco. Chester Arthur signed this act into law in 1882. For ten points, name this act that barred immigration from a large Asian country.", "answer": "<b> Chinese Exclusion</b> Act", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "This leader was opposed by \u201cJafari the Brainless\u201d and the Rashidian brothers. This leader resigned after his Minister of War nomination was blocked, prompting the leftist Tudeh Party to take to the streets. Kermit Roosevelt helped disseminate<em> firman</em> declarations opposing this leader. MI6 and the CIA joined forces to overthrow this leader in Operation Ajax after he nationalized the AIOC. For ten points, name this secular Prime Minister of Iran who was overthrown in a 1953 coup.", "answer": "Mohammad<b> Mossadegh</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "This song plays over the opening credits of Stanley Kubrick\u2019s film<em> Paths of Glory</em>. The lyrics to this song implore, \u201cLet\u2019s march, let\u2019s march,\u201d and it opens with the words \u201cArise, children of the fatherland.\u201dPhrases from this song and \u201cGod Save the Tsar\u201d are repeatedly used to represent opposing armies in Tchaikovsky\u2019s<em> 1812 Overture</em>. Patrons of Rick\u2019s American Cafe sing this song to drown out the Nazi soldiers in the film<em> Casablanca</em>. For ten points, name this national anthem of France.", "answer": "La<b> Marseillaise</b> (prompt on descriptions of the French national anthem)", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Other Fine Arts - Misc Arts"}, {"question": "A bust of this man in \u201cSevere style\u201d is considered the \u201cfirst true portrait of an individual European.\u201dIn one plot, this man fled Greece after being implicated as a co-conspirator with the treasonous Pausanias. This general at Marathon was elected archon and called for increased emphasis on his city\u2019s naval power, which proved instrumental at a 470 BC battle against the forces of Xerxes the Great. For ten points, name this leader of Greek forces against the Persians at the Battle of Salamis.", "answer": "<b> Themistocles</b>", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {"question": "In the aftermath of this event, Robert Hunter wrote, \u201cOne way or another, this darkness got to give\u201dfor the track \u201cNew Speedway Boogie.\u201d During this event, Paul Kanter sarcastically thanked security for smashing \u201cMarty Balin in the face.\u201d A video crew recorded a stabbing during this event, footage of which was used in the documentary<em> Gimme Shelter</em>. The Hells Angels provided security for the Rolling Stones at, for ten points, what failed \u201cWoodstock of the West,\u201d a 1969 free concert in California?", "answer": "<b> Altamont</b> Free Concert (accept<b> Altamont</b> Speedway Free Festival, accept<b> Altamont</b> Affair)", "metadata": "Trash - Trash"}, {}, {"question": "During this battle, an attack from the south forced one commander to flee across Brouwer\u2019s millpond. American troops were forced to use their muskets as clubs against oncoming Hessian troops at Battle Pass during this engagement. Israel Putnam was promoted prior to this battle, which occurred four months after the Siege of Boston. Though William Howe won this battle, George Washington was able to flee across the East River from Brooklyn Heights. For ten points, name this 1776 battle.", "answer": "Battle of<b> Long Island</b> (accept Battle of<b> Brooklyn</b> Heights before mentioned)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "In this region, Daoud Bolad led a separatist movement after disputes over hakurat land rights in the 1980s. Slovene activist Tomo Kriznar was arrested for videotaping atrocities committed in this region. The Zaghawa and Masalit ethnic groups have been forced to flee this region. The Janjaweed militias have been accused of violence in this region while under the command of Omar al-Bashir. For ten points, name this region, the location of the genocide of thousands of non-Arabs in Sudan.", "answer": "<b> Darfur</b> (accept War in<b> Darfur</b> or<b> Darfur</b> genocide)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "After being forced to flee Nazi Germany, this philosopher stated that only \u201cthe gloomiest predictions have any plausibility.\u201d This philosopher claimed that the \u201cdamaged life\u201d had led to fascism in his book <em>Minima Moralia</em>. This student of Alban Berg had plans to complete Berg\u2019s opera Lulu and notably dismissed jazz as part of the \u201cculture industry.\u201d For ten points, name this German Marxist philosopher, who collaborated with Max Horkheimer on<em> Dialectic of Enlightenment</em>.", "answer": "Theodor W.<b> Adorno</b>", "metadata": "Philosophy - Philosophy"}, {}, {"question": "At this battle, a group of nearly 2,000 mercenaries under Philibert of Chand\u00b4ee proved instrumental to the winning army. The Stanley family assisted the victor in surrounding the losing army of this battle. Henry Percy was briefly imprisoned after this battle, where he served under a man who killed the Princes in the Tower. The future Henry VII was the victor at this battle which resulted in the death of Richard III. For ten points, name this 1485 battle, the last major engagement of the Wars of the Roses.", "answer": "Battle of<b> Bosworth</b> Field", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "That institution containing the Skull and Bones society was named after this man in 1718. For ten points, who is this man who names an Ivy League institution in New Haven, Connecticut?", "answer": "Elihu<b> Yale</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>After this man had a dispute with his sister-in-law, Dagmar Havlov\u00b4a, he sold his fifty percent stake in the Lucerna Palace on Wenceslas Square that his grandfather built. This leader started several dissident initiatives including the (+) Charter 77 and the Committee for the Defense of the Unjustly Prosecuted. This man led the Civic Forum when it dominated the first free election in (*)</b> Czechoslovakia in forty-four years in 1990. For ten points, name this man, the namesake of the international airport in Prague and the first president of the Czech Republic.", "answer": "Vaclav<b> Havel</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>Julius Caesar Chappelle gave a speech at this building in 1890 promoting a federal law to allow Blacks to vote. The namesake of this building inherited a massive shipping empire,</b> <b>because he went against his uncle\u2019s wishes and chose (+)</b> <b>not to marry. This building is</b> <b>named after a slave trader from a Huguenot family. The site of many patriotic speeches, a noted Ann Whitney statue of one of those speakers, (*) </b> Samuel Adams, stands at its eastern end near a statue of Mayor Kevin White. For ten points, name this \u201cCradle of Liberty,\u201d a meeting hall in Boston.", "answer": "<b> Faneuil</b> Hall", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>Early in this man\u2019s career, he failed at making saddles and repairing clocks. This artist spent three years studying painting with Benjamin West before returning to Maryland and</b> <b>joining the (+)</b> <b>Sons of Liberty. This man organized the first U.S. science expedition and</b> <b>founded the Philadelphia Museum. This polymath had sons named Titian and Rembrandt and painted a self-portrait titled</b><em><b> The Artist in His Museum</b></em><b>. This man is perhaps best known for depicting (*) </b> men like Nathanael Greene and Thomas Jefferson in his portraits of Revolutionary War figures. For ten points, name this patriot and painter.", "answer": "<b> C</b>harles Willson<b> Peale</b>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Visual Fine Arts"}, {"question": "<b>This man popularized the term \u201cMiddle East\u201d after publishing an article on \u201cThe Persian Gulf and its International Relations.\u201d One work by this officer, inspired by Antoine-Henri</b> <b>Jomini, advocated for the usage of (+)</b> <b>\u201cdecisive battle\u201d and blockade. Some have argued</b> <b>that use of this man\u2019s theories led to the Japanese defeat in World War Two. This man\u2019s writing inspired Alfred (*) </b> von Tirpitz to plan for the annihilation of the Royal Navy, sparking an arms race between Germany and Great Britain. For ten points, name this American naval officer who penned<em> The Influence of Sea Power Upon History</em>.", "answer": "Alfred Thayer<b> Mahan</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {}, {}, {}], "bonuses": []}